ebid.net 2019-04-16

# eBid Help - FAQ > Registration, Upgrading and Logging in on eBid United States

## Registration, Upgrading and Logging in

  1. **How do I register with eBid.**
  2. **How do I upgrade my account?**
  3. **How do I stop my subscription?**
  4. **Why can't I see the "Stop My Subscription" option in the dropdown menu on the "My Subscription" page?**
  5. **I don't think my email validation link arrived.**
  6. **Why do you have to email me a validation email? I want to bid now!**
  7. **I want to choose my own password.**
  8. **I've forgotten my password.**
  9. **I can't login to the eBid Forums area.**
  10. **Do I need to give you a credit card?**
  11. **I've been told I need to validate my account.**
  12. **I've been told my account is on Hold.**
  13. **Is it free to join eBid?**
  14. **Why is my username struck out?**
  15. **How can i change my username?**
  16. **Add eBid to your address book to stop emails being classed as Spam.**
  17. **How do I claim my free eBid cap?**
  18. **I'm entering the correct password but it's not logging me in?**
  19. **Do I have to give you my personal details?**
  20. **How do you assure the privacy of my information?**
  21. **How do I close my account?**
  22. **I've been told my account is on hold because I've reported spam.**
  23. **Can I view the site in another language?**
  24. **Can I import my feedback from another marketplace site?**

### 1) How do I register with eBid.

It's simple. Just go to [the registration page](https://www.ebid.net/us/register/), fill out the form, choose which account plan you want (BUYER, SELLER or SELLER+) and submit it. You'll receive a confirmation link by email that you'll need to click on then you will then have unlimited access to eBid.To ensure you are registering on the correct eBid site please go to the [eBid.net](http://www.ebid.net/) country selection page and select your country of residence.

Register as BUYER only you'll be able to bid and buy, not sell.

If you are listing an item for auction you will need to either upgrade to SELLER or SELLER+, see next FAQ below. A comparison of eBid account plans can be seen below also.

### 2) How do I upgrade my account?

You can upgrade immediately when you register by choosing SELLER or SELLER+ on the registration form. To upgrade any time after registering visit the "My Subscriptions" section of "My eBid". The details for each account plan can be seen below. This page will also show you what current plan you are on.

**SELLER** : upgrade fee : Lifetime $0.00

**SELLER+** : upgrade fee :7 Day $1.99   |   30 Day $6.99   |   90 Day $16.99   |   365 Day $54.99   |   Lifetime $99.98 

SELLER+ Lifetime is currently available for $49.99 if upgrade takes place within 24 hours of registration OR any other upgrade. 

Please note that all SELLER+ subscriptions apart from lifetime are recurring. SELLER+ subscriptions may be cancelled at any time via the dropdown menu on the "My eBid" > "My Subscription" section. 

If you require an invoice for your subscription, this can be printed from the "My eBid" > "My Subscription" > "Print Invoice" link at the bottom right hand side of the page. 

#### Compare Account Plans

| BUYER | SELLER | SELLER+  
---|---|---|---  
Can Place Bids, Make Offers & BuyNow | Y | Y | Y  
Can List Items For Sale | N | Y | Y  
Listing Fee | N | 0.00 | 0.00  
Final Value Fee | N | 3% | Choice of 0% (Free) or 2% (Gallery)  
Access to Ninja Lister App for Bulk Uploading and Importing from Other Marketplaces | N | Y | Y  
Integrated PayPal Checkout for their Buyers | N | N | Y  
Can Import Feedback from other Marketplaces | N | N | Y  
Items Listed on Google Shopping | N | N | Y  
Items Listed on Bing Shopping | N | N | Y (SELLER+ Lifetime Beta Access)  
Video Descriptions | N | N | Y  
Thumbnail Photo in Search Results | N | N | Y  
Free Photos | N | 1 | 15  
BuyNow Price Available | N | N | Y  
Auto Extend Available | N | N | Y  
Cross Promotions | N | N | Y  
Access to eBid Spreadsheet Bulk Uploader | N | N | Y  
Import Listings from Other Marketplaces Directly | N | N | Y (SELLER+ Lifetime Beta Access)  
Can List Private Auctions? | N | N | Y  
Customer Invoicing System | N | N | Y  
Grouping Multiple Auctions | N | N | Y  
BuyNow Only (Fixed Price) Format | N | N | Y  
Run Until Sold (Store Inventory) | N | N | Y  
Free eBid Stores | N | 0 | 5  
Scheduled Starting Times | N | N | Y  
Scheduled Closing Times | N | N | Y  
Can Create Discounts/Sales | N | N | Y  
"Make an Offer" available on your listings? | N | N | Y  
All SELLER+ options are available to SELLER if they choose the "Platinum" featured option when listing an item. A small listing fee is chargeable for this.  
  
### 3) How do I stop my subscription?

If you have a SELLER+ account and wish to cancel your subscription, go to "My eBid" > "My Subscription" and choose the "Stop My Subscription" option in the drop down menu. Please note your existing subscription will continue until its expiry date but will not be renewed on expiry. 

### 4) Why can't I see the "Stop My Subscription" option in the dropdown menu on the "My Subscription" page?

If you have a SELLER+ account and cannot see the "Stop My Subscription" option in the dropdown menu on the "My eBid > My Subscription" page, the most likely reason is that eBid do not hold a card reference against your account and therefore we are unable to rollover your subscription or collect outstanding fees. Your last subscription may have already expired. You can check your last subscription expiry at the bottom on the "My Subscription" page. To rectify the problem update your registered card using the link provided on the "My Subscription" page. If you do not wish to continue with a SELLER+ subscription, we suggest changing your subscription to Seller, which does not incur subscription fees. 

### 5) I don't think my email validation link arrived.

When you first register with eBid you will be sent an email to the email address you registered with. You will need to click the link located on this email to let us know your email address is valid. If you haven't received the validation email or have just started seeing this error message then : 

Either 

  * If you're a brand new user and do not see your validation email in your email inbox yet then please check your "Spam" or "Junk Email" folders as on rare occasions our emails are routed there. If our email does not appear to be anywhere then you should add donotreply@ebid.net to your contacts/address book and then [re-request the validation email by entering your email address or username into the Lost Password form here](https://www.ebid.net/us/help/forgotten-password/). 
  * Perhaps you typed your email address incorrectly (most common reason). It happens often. If you try and register another account on eBid it will not allow it if your email address is already in our database. So if you are able to register again then it means you typed it incorrectly the first time!. If you made a purchase and realise you used the wrong email address then use "Help > Contact Us" and we will take a look for you and attempt to merge the two accounts. 
  * If you've been a member of eBid for a while and could successfully login before today but have started see a "validation required" error then [request another email here](https://www.ebid.net/us/help/forgotten-password/). 

### 6) Why do you have to email me a validation email? I want to bid now!

We send you a validation email so that we know that you can receive email at the address you provide to us. It's our way of authenticating your registration. By doing this, we avoid problems of incorrect email addresses preventing a deal from happening, and of people registering other people without their knowledge and placing bids on their behalf. 

### 7) I want to choose my own password.

When you first register you choose your own password. It can be changed on the "My eBid" > "My Personal Details" page. 

### 8) I've forgotten my password.

If your username and password don't seem to be working, firstly check you are entering it correctly, you'll be amazed how many people mistake a small "L" for a capital "i" or have an incorrect computer clock. Secondly you can [visit our reminder page](https://www.ebid.net/us/help/forgotten-password/) where you can enter your username or email address and be sent a password reset link by email to your registered email address. The email you receive will identify the IP address of the person who requested the reset. You can [find your IP address](http://www.whatsanip.com/) here if you wish to confirm it came from you. 

### 9) I can't login to the eBid Forums area.

Logging into the eBid Forums area is done using the same username and password you use for the main eBid site. If you don't seem to be able to login this could be due to you updating your password at the Forums site without realising. This option has now been removed. Just visit the "My Personal Details" page of My eBid to change your password, this will update your details for the main site as well as the eBid Forums area. 

### 10) Do I need to give you a credit card?

**Registration is FREE.** If you are listing an item for auction you will need to upgrade your account to **SELLER** or **SELLER+** status, each will give you differing access to our selling facilities. A credit or debit card can be used via our secure payment providers. A credit or debit card is currently the only method of obtaining a Security Subscription. **SELLER** requires a free validation of your card, **SELLER+** requires a 7,30,90,365 day or Lifetime Security Subscription to be purchased. To see current SELLER+ Security Subscription prices and to upgrade view the My Subscriptions section of My eBid. 

### 11) I've been told I need to validate my account.

On the email you receive when you register there is a link you must click on that tells us you received the email ok. If you haven't done this yet then do it now. The email should arrive immediately after you register. If you haven't received the email then go to our lost password page. You can enter your username or email address here and submit. The validation email will be sent out to you again. 

### 12) I've been told my account is on Hold.

To keep eBid as clutter free to allow genuine sellers a clean and efficient marketplace in which to trade, we ask all sellers to not break our [posting rules](https://www.ebid.net/us/help_selling.php#faq-27)  
If any of your items cross this boundary, ALL your auctions will be deleted without notice and your account placed on hold. When you try and login while your account is on hold you will find you are locked out. To remove this ban, please email us using the contact form in the Help section stating the item(s) you posted to create this ban and that you will not post such items any more. Please do not email us asking us what you did wrong, a simple apology will re-open your account almost immediately whereas a long winded email conversation will waste ours and your time.  
If you state you will refrain from posting banned items and are caught a second time, the same will happen.  
If you are caught a third time your account will be locked on a permanent basis. It is up to you to read the posting rules and abide by them, users are told about the posting rules when they start an auction. "I didn't realise" won't be a valid excuse!  
Continuous negative feedback will also see your account placed on hold. Always make sure your first feedback is positive otherwise your account could be investigated.  
Holders of multiple accounts will also be placed on hold.  
Users suspected of bidding on their own auctions (shilling or shill bidding) will see their accounts placed on hold.  
Users with incomplete address details will be placed on hold. 

### 13) Is it free to join eBid?

Joining eBid is completely free, just sign up with our form [here](https://www.ebid.net/us/register/). You can be bidding within a few seconds. Once you have joined then you will have the option to upgrade to **SELLER** or **SELLER+** status to allow yourself to start selling. 

### 14) Why is my username struck out?

Your account has been placed on hold. The most common reason for this is users found to have not read our posting rules and subsequently breaking them, they will be placed on hold without notice and in many cases have all current auctions removed immediately. Please make sure you read our [posting rules](https://www.ebid.net/us/help_selling.php#faq-27) before contacting us. 

### 15) How can i change my username?

If you have registered and have made a mistake with your username or have a valid reason for changing, please contact us via the "Contact Us" tab on our "Help" index page section and if applicable we will make the necessary changes. There is a limit of 18 characters. We cannot accept spaces in the Username and characters such as stops and hyphens are not compatible, although underscores are acceptable. For security reasons, on the Help Section Contact Form please ensure you enter your registered email address. 

### 16) Add eBid to your address book to stop emails being classed as Spam.

**AOL Email Version 8**

  * Within your "Inbox" Click on the "Mail options" arrow then click on "Address Book".
  * Having clicked on "Address Book" another screen will pop up.
  * Click on the "Add Contact" button then either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the screen name section.

**AOL Email Version 9**

  * Within your "Inbox" Click on the "Mail options" arrow then click on "Address Book".
  * Having clicked on "Address Book" another screen will pop up.
  * Click on the "+" sign with "Add" written beneath it.
  * An "Address Card" will then appear. Either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the screen name section.

**Gmail**

  * Within your "Inbox" open an eBid email.
  * Click on the "More options" link to the top right-hand side of the message.
  * Click on the "Add sender to contact list" option.
  * The highlighted message "The sender has been added to your contacts list" will then appear if this has been done correctly.

**Orange**

  * Within your "Inbox" click on the "My Settings" link in the top right-hand corner just above the "Search" button.
  * Scroll down to the bottom of the page to the "My Settings" area.
  * On the right-hand side there is a box marked "Security" and the first link is the "Approved List".
  * Click the "Approved list" link.
  * Either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the box beneath "Add a new address or new domain name" and click on "Add".

**MSN Hotmail/Outlook**

  * Click the "Contacts" tab that runs across the top centre of your Inbox.
  * Click on "Safe-list".
  * Either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the box and click on "Add".

**Yahoo**

  * Within your "Inbox" click on the "Options" link in the top right-hand side of the screen beneath the "Search" button.
  * A list of mail options will appear on-screen.
  * Click on the "Address Book" link in the "Options" box on the left-hand side of the screen.
  * Click on either of the "Add Contact" buttons.
  * Either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the "email" box and click on "Save".
  * Then click "Done".

**Virgin**

  * Within your "Inbox" click on the "Contacts" tab situated above the list of your new messages.
  * Click on the "New Contact" button.
  * Either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the "email 1" box and click on "Save and close".

**Microsoft Outlook**

  * Go to "Actions" menu.
  * Select "Junk e-mail".
  * Select "Add sender to safe sender list". 

**Ntlworld**

  * From your "Inbox", click on the "Addresses" link in the Main menu on the left-hand side.
  * On the "Addresses" page, click "Create Address".
  * A form for entering new address names appears.
  * Either type or copy and paste donotreply@ebid.net into the "*Email" box.
  * Enter a "Nickname" such as "eBid" into the "*Nickname" box.
  * Click "Save".
  * The address is created.

**Tiscali**

  * Within your "Inbox" open an eBid email.
  * Click on the "Add to Address Book" link at the top right-hand corner of the message.
  * The "Address Book" should already contain the email address (donotreply@ebid.net).
  * You will need to fill in both the Firstname and Surname fields with something relevant such as "eBid".

### 17) How do I claim my free eBid cap?

After upgrading to SELLER+ Lifetime, simply contact us via our contact form on the Helpdesk index page with your username. We will check it out and mail to your registered address. 

### 18) I'm entering the correct password but it's not logging me in?

This is one of the most common questions we are asked. Please check the list below prior to contacting us. 

  * You will **not** be logged in if you have CAPS LOCK on, passwords are case sensitive. You will **not** be logged in if you type the wrong password, i, I, l, L, 1 all look the same but a computer sees them as different as S and P.
  * You will **not** be logged in if your computer clock is wrong, the cookies we set are dependant on a correct clock.
  * Try logging in using an alternative browser such as Mozilla Firefox or Google Chrome.

### 19) Do I have to give you my personal details?

**Yes**. We do require your personal details from you, and all information provided must be accurate. Once registered, you may be asked to provide us with additional documentation if further verification is sought or required. If you do not provide valid information as requested we may immediately suspend your account without notice. 

### 20) How do you assure the privacy of my information?

We value our own privacy and yours, and do not abuse your information. Specifically: 

  * We disclose your information to other eBid users only when a sale is made between two parties.
  * All the personal data entered is recorded and stored in a secure database.
  * We will not sell or give your name to other organizations for them to contact you.
  * We will disclose your contact information to other users who have a valid reason to contact you.
  * We will use your contact information to send you invoices plus any notifications, newsletters and announcements you opt into via My eBid > My Notifications.

**Full Privacy Policy**

-How eBid Uses your Personal Data.  
In this section we have set out:  
  .. The general categories of personal data that we may process;  
  .. In the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data;  
  .. The purposes for which we may process personal data; and  
  .. The legal bases of the processing.

We may process data about your use of our website/apps and services ("usage data"). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website/apps navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing the use of the website/apps and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent or legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website/apps and services.

We may process your account data ("account data"). The account data may include your name, email address, telephone number, address, if you are an individual or business and your business information. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website/apps, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website/apps and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is the proper administration of our website/apps and business and the performance of such services.

We may process your information included in your personal profile on our website/apps ("profile data").The profile data may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures or logos, company logos. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website/apps and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent or our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website/apps and business or the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at you request, to enter into such a contract.

We may process your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our services ("service data"). The service data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website/apps, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website/apps and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website.

We may process information that you post for publication on our website/apps or through our services ("publication data"). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website/apps and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website/apps and business.

We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services ("enquiry data"). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you

We may process information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information ("customer relationship data"). The customer relationship data may include your name, telephone number, address email address and information contained in communications between us and you. The customer relationship data may be processed for the purposes of managing our relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of those communications and promoting our products and services to customers. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper management of our customer relationships and interactions between you and potential or otherwise counterparties.

We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website/apps ("transaction data"). The transaction data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website/apps and business.

We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters ("notification data"). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract ("registration").

We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us ("correspondence data"). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website/apps will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website/apps contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website/apps and business and communications with users.

We may process data about your products and services. This data may include product information, product location and shipping details and charges. This data may be processed for specify purposes. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely specify legitimate interests in the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.

We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.

In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this section, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

-Providing Your Personal Data to Others.  
We may disclose your personal data to any members or any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy. Information about our group of companies can be found at the bottom of the page.

We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

We may disclose personal data to our suppliers or subcontractors.  
Financial transactions relating to our website/apps and services are OR may be handled by our payment services providers, Barclay Merchant Services, Paypal and Pay360. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. 

We may disclose your enquiry data to one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and services identified on our website/apps for the purpose of enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party's use of your personal data.

In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this section, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

-International Transfers of Your Personal Data  
In this section, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

We and our other group companies have offices and facilities in the UK, USA and EU. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission. 

The hosting facilities for our website/apps are situated in USA. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.

You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website/apps or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

-Retaining and Deleting Personal Data  
This section sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

We will retain your personal data as follows:  
  ..Personal data category or categories will be retained for a minimum period of 6 years following registration or cookie collection and for a maximum period of 6 years following registration with financial and transaction data.

In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on the following criteria: Activity as a seller, buyer or registered member with trading or financial history. 

Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

-Amendments  
We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website/apps.

You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

We may notify you of significant changes to this policy by email or through the private messaging system on our website/apps.

-Your Rights  
In this section, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Your principal rights under data protection law are:  
  (a)    the right to access;  
  (b)    the right to rectification;  
  (c)    the right to erasure;  
  (d)    the right to restrict processing;  
  (e)    the right to object to processing;  
  (f)    the right to data portability;  
  (g)    the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and  
  (h)    the right to withdraw consent.

   You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can access your personal data by visiting your My eBid > My Details section when logged into our website/apps.

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of lYou have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to yoparticular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:  
  (a)    consent; or  
  (b)    that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,

       and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data via your My eBid > My Details section, in addition to the other methods specified above.

-About Cookies  
A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

-Cookies That We Use  
We use cookies for the following purposes:  
  (a)    Authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website/apps and as you navigate our website/apps  
  (b)    We use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website/apps   
  (c)    We use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalise the website/apps for you   
  (d)    Security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website/apps and services   
  (e)    Advertising - we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you  
  (f)    Analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website/apps and services  
  (g)    Cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally

-Cookies Used By our Service Providers  
Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website/apps.

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website/apps. Google Analytics gathers information about website/apps use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website/apps is used to create reports about the use of our website/apps. Google's privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website/apps. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website/apps and on other website/appss across the web using cookies. OR We publish Google AdSense advertisements on our website/apps. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website/apps and on other website/appss across the web using cookies. This behaviour tracking allows Google to tailor the advertisements that you see on other website/appss to reflect your interests (but we do not publish interest-based advertisements on our website/apps). You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.

-Managing Cookies  
Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

  (a)    https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);  
  (b)    https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website/Apps-preferences (Firefox);  
  (c)    http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);  
  (d)    https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);  
  (e)    https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and  
  (f)    https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).

Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many website/Appss.

If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website/Apps.  

### 21) How do I close my account?

To close your account please open a support ticket advising you wish to do so. For security reasons please ensure the email comes from your registered email address and please advise your registered telephone number. Please also ensure you have a zero account balance. Click the HELP link in the page header and follow the tab to CONTACT US. If you simply want to stop a recurring SELLER+ subscription, just downgrade to SELLER status via "My eBid > My Subscriptions". 

### 22) I've been told my account is on hold because I've reported spam.

Some eBidders have contacted us to tell us their eBid accounts are inaccessible after they have reported emails we've sent them as spam. We don't send spam so please don't report any of our emails as spam, it affects our reputation with email providers greatly when this happens. 

Please visit "My eBid" > "My eMails" and turn off any emails you don't want. Also some people have been reporting forum thread subscriptions that they asked to be sent to them as spam, please, if you don't want it don't sign up for it, and definitely don't mark it as spam when it hits your inbox. There are links on every email we send (apart from our fee invoices) to stop them being sent to you. 

### 23) Can I view the site in another language?

If you are viewing an eBid site on which the local language is NOT English then you will be able to view the site in English if you wish. Scroll to the bottom of the page and you will see a dropdown menu with English as an option, just select English and submit. 

Please note that you will be required to list your items in the local language still if you wish your items to be uploaded to Google Shopping. eg. eBid Germany, you can view the site in English but your items will need to be listed in German still. 

### 24) Can I import my feedback from another marketplace site?

See the [Feedback FAQ](https://www.ebid.net/us/help/ebid-feedback-system/#faq-8).
